<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-06-14T23:39:08+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/</id><title type="html">Ezgi Çınarlı | Freelance Product Designer &amp;amp; Illustrator</title><subtitle>Portfolio of Ezgi Çınarlı, Freelance Product Designer &amp; Illustrator living in Den Haag, Netherlands</subtitle><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><entry><title type="html">Nice to Have ⇾ Acrylic Illustrations</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-acrylic-illustrations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nice to Have ⇾ Acrylic Illustrations" /><published>2016-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/nice-to-have-acrylic-illustrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-acrylic-illustrations/">&lt;p&gt;“Nice to Have” , “Producing delicately created objects for fine living.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following illustrations are made with acrylic paint and brush on paper for our second collection in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Giclée printed on Archival Hahnemühle Photo Canvas, 320 gsm, %100 Cotton, White Canvas using Ultrachrome HD Pigment based inks from Epson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may visit www.nicetohave.me to see more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">“Nice to Have” , “Producing delicately created objects for fine living.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nice to Have ⇾ Animal Drawings with ink</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-animal-drawings-with-ink/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nice to Have ⇾ Animal Drawings with ink" /><published>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/nice-to-have-animal-drawings-with-ink</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-animal-drawings-with-ink/">&lt;p&gt;In 2012 i co-founded a brand called “Nice to Have” , “Producing delicately created objects for fine living.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first collection was launched in March 2015 with various products; including artworks, tote bags and cushion covers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Animals and their incredible complexity has always fascinated me. I have been interested in animal stories; their intelligence, skills and culture. Searching for their features, characteristics, survival skills, chasing exclusive species.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original drawings are made on paper with ink, a perfect way to draw detailed animals. Then each animal drawing posed on silk, and screen printed by hand on high quality fine art paper and canvas fabric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every single tag is crafted exclusively from poplar plywood, sanded by hand until it gets smooth enough. Animal stories are engraved on tags with the production date and the weather condition of specific day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">In 2012 i co-founded a brand called “Nice to Have” , “Producing delicately created objects for fine living.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fiat ⇾ Smart Race Autoshow</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/fiat-smartrace-autoshow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fiat ⇾ Smart Race Autoshow" /><published>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/fiat-smartrace-autoshow</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/fiat-smartrace-autoshow/">&lt;p&gt;Fiat Smart Race is an interactive slot car racing game presented at İstanbul Autoshow 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed and created a multi player physical interface that can be controlled and played remotely by any smart phone. So anyone who is passing by could scan a QR code on their smart phones and instantly start racing with custom made vertical slot car including Fiat Panda and Fiat 500&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">Fiat Smart Race is an interactive slot car racing game presented at İstanbul Autoshow 2012.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opet ⇾ Infographic</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/opet-infographic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opet ⇾ Infographic" /><published>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/opet-infographic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/opet-infographic/">&lt;p&gt;We created this infographic piece for Opet, a Turkish petroleum company founded in 1992.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">We created this infographic piece for Opet, a Turkish petroleum company founded in 1992.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Akfel ⇾ WGC Paris Multitouch Application</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Akfel ⇾ WGC Paris Multitouch Application" /><published>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application/">&lt;p&gt;Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach was capturing audience attention on the field with an unexpected object, a space capsule coming from the future with a message in it. The message was composed of three key future projections; Climate Change, Health and Economics in the future. Story focus and our goal were to raise awareness and target emotional, perceptual experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 21st of May, we had the approval of capsule designs, materials, construction plans, key visuals and concept overall. Except we had no storyboard and two months to deliver the thing on the field. To cover up roughly we built a 4 meters long, 2.3 meters wide and 2.2 meters high made of aluminium space capsule looking experience area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We planted five LCD TV’s inside, three of them were the main screens which was feed by a multitouch application streaming 3240 x 1920 pixels of data and two of them were on the sides acting as a control panel, status updates and fictional settings. Again on both sides, we had 8 highlighted subjects in seven segment displays. Displaying real-time numbers of deaths today, births today, deaths caused by cancer and deaths caused by the hunger for instance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nice to Have ⇾ Product Design, Branding, Photography</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-product-design-branding-photography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nice to Have ⇾ Product Design, Branding, Photography" /><published>2015-06-08T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-08T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/nice-to-have-product-design-branding-photography</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/nicetohave-product-design-branding-photography/">&lt;p&gt;In 2012 we co-founded the brand called “Nice to Have”, “producing delicately created objects for fine living”. First collection and online shop was launched in 2015, after a short period of time opened a retail store in İstanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you feel about an object is important, sometimes we encounter a few that we have to use even we don’t like. We believe that the objects people own in their lives, are small reflections of how they choose to live it or had to..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We appreciate conscious consumption, investing in quality and the idea of owning things for life. Our goal is to create objects that are pleasing to the eye for years to come and durable enough for frequent uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the aspects of good design and aesthetics, user friendly experience is one of our priority. We produce our products using the best possible material and processing methods with local artisans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe in heritage of knowledge and experiences shape our lives. Learning is the key to keep our imagination alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may take a look at what we have been up to in our retail and online store.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">In 2012 we co-founded the brand called “Nice to Have”, “producing delicately created objects for fine living”. First collection and online shop was launched in 2015, after a short period of time opened a retail store in İstanbul.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Tilt Machine</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Tilt Machine" /><published>2015-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve created a motion tracking enabled, physical tilt game for Türkiye İş Bankası. Idea was to let people experience how easy it is to use bank’s mobile application for online banking just with a simple gesture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coin based game starts with a 1 Turkish Lira, after a coin inserted, one has to stand in the marked place and raise hand. When Kinect sensor acknowledges the person, a countdown begins and new “game coin” gets released from the slot to top left path. Goal is to get the coin through all the banking operations which are Money Transfer, Investment and Saving. We named these three as gates and each gate had its own attitude. If a coin slides into money transfer, another coin releases from opposite side or if it slides into investment gate, it spits out two coins to go on with. In the end users win the game when both coins slides into savings gate. Eventually the coin acceptor releases the initial real coin user inserted to start the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was another challenging project. As we needed to control single axis motion of a structure in realtime, we installed a 12 Nm industrial stepper motor coupled with 1:100 reduction gear right in the centre of structure origin. Rotating part was about 2 meters high, 1 meter wide and weigh around 180 kilograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 10 Hitec servos running together to control all 6 flags, 3 coin release slots and the coin acceptor’s real coin slide out channel. Two units of 25 rpm dc motors used for the propellers and 1500 neopixel led’s running on four led micro controllers. In total there were three Arduino Uno and one Arduino Mega used to control the whole electro mechanical system. Microsoft Kinect was used for the real time motion tracking technology as physical controlling interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 10 Hitec servos running together to control all 6 flags, 3 coin release slots and the coin acceptor’s real coin slide out channel. Two units of 25 rpm dc motors used for the propellers and 1500 neopixel led’s running on four led micro controllers. In total there were three Arduino Uno and one Arduino Mega used to control the whole electro mechanical system. Microsoft Kinect was used for the real time motion tracking technology as physical controlling interface.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve created a motion tracking enabled, physical tilt game for Türkiye İş Bankası. Idea was to let people experience how easy it is to use bank’s mobile application for online banking just with a simple gesture.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ İşBox Kinect</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ İşBox Kinect" /><published>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation featuring real-time and pre-defined skeleton tracking and matching based on human recognition using Xbox Kinect in February 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to create an interactive game to promote bank’s Kinect controlled, console based banking application for Xbox One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a shooting in studio with a choreographer and two performers, creating six different clips featuring various banking figures for three music genres. While doing this we also recorded performers skeleton data in order to match the real-time input generated by a participant in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 or more banking and dancing figures were targeted for each song and if participant’s were good enough to act exactly or nearly the same, they were motivated with supers associated with banking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When playing, we took their photos and printed them out like a slip when they are finished.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation featuring real-time and pre-defined skeleton tracking and matching based on human recognition using Xbox Kinect in February 2015.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aygaz ⇾ Step Into The Future</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/aygaz-step-into-the-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aygaz ⇾ Step Into The Future" /><published>2014-07-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/aygaz-step-into-the-future.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/aygaz-step-into-the-future/">&lt;p&gt;Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach was capturing audience attention on the field with an unexpected object, a space capsule coming from the future with a message in it. The message was composed of three key future projections; Climate Change, Health and Economics in the future. Story focus and our goal were to raise awareness and target emotional, perceptual experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 21st of May, we had the approval of capsule designs, materials, construction plans, key visuals and concept overall. Except we had no storyboard and two months to deliver the thing on the field. To cover up roughly we built a 4 meters long, 2.3 meters wide and 2.2 meters high made of aluminium space capsule looking experience area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We planted five LCD TV’s inside, three of them were the main screens which was feed by a multitouch application streaming 3240 x 1920 pixels of data and two of them were on the sides acting as a control panel, status updates and fictional settings. Again on both sides, we had 8 highlighted subjects in seven segment displays. Displaying real-time numbers of deaths today, births today, deaths caused by cancer and deaths caused by the hunger for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each topic had 35 to 45 seconds of animation content to narrate the story, at the end of each scene, users faced with an interactive 3d world geometry to go through the details of just explained. For example after the Climate Change scene an interactive scenario opens up to let user browse the drastic escalation of carbon dioxide and nitrogen emission between 1956 to 2056. Throughout the story every crucial detailed data was mined from various articles, reports, future projections and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall journey actually starts with a push of a button on the back side of the space capsule. When button kicks in an automatic door opens up while sending a signal to an Arduino board which triggers another Arduino board with two real time clocks to light up seven segments. Another signal goes to main PC which runs the multitouch application and video feed to initialize the welcome screen. Third signal going from the main Arduino board to the second PC which runs the side screens. Fourth signal goes to led control panel for lighting the ceiling which is responsive to the current content playing on main screens which makes led control panel synced in realtime to the main pc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes it was a complicated setup and in the end we found our self controlling every bit with a network of Arduino’s talking each other even when logging out from the capsule. There is a button inside which is yellow by the way, when you press that button, automatic doors opens up, system shuts down and CCTV stops operating until the next push from outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 52 days of sleepless nights, lots of calories and chain of events ruled by Murphy we delivered the space capsule on time for the roadshow. It was a huge experience for all of us and full of education on every step of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ajans Press ⇾ Courier Ad</title><link href="https://www.thisisezgi.me/ajans-press-courier-ad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ajans Press ⇾ Courier Ad" /><published>2014-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.thisisezgi.me/ajans-press-courier-ad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thisisezgi.me/ajans-press-courier-ad/">&lt;p&gt;Ajans Press, the pioneer and leader of media monitoring business in Turkey, has been providing service since the day it was founded in 1953. In addition to press, television, radio and internet monitoring and media analysis service, Ajans Press also provides news agency monitoring, sectoral agenda, tape-scripting and translation services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed and directed a TV Ad for their new courier service “Ajans Press Kurye”, the new company focuses on cooperative distribution of promotional materials etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ezgi Çınarlı</name></author><summary type="html">Ajans Press, the pioneer and leader of media monitoring business in Turkey, has been providing service since the day it was founded in 1953. In addition to press, television, radio and internet monitoring and media analysis service, Ajans Press also provides news agency monitoring, sectoral agenda, tape-scripting and translation services.</summary></entry></feed>