<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-01T22:14:40+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Özgür Atmaca | Multidisciplinary Product Designer</title><subtitle>Portfolio of Özgür Atmaca, Multidisciplinary Product Designer working in Rotterdam, Netherlands</subtitle><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><entry><title type="html">Fiat ⇾ Smart Race Autoshow</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fiat-smartrace-autoshow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fiat ⇾ Smart Race Autoshow" /><published>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-08-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fiat-smartrace-autoshow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fiat-smartrace-autoshow/">&lt;p&gt;Fiat Smart Race is an interactive slot car racing game presented at İstanbul Autoshow 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We developed and created a multi player physical interface that can be controlled and played remotely by any smart phone. So anyone who is passing by could scan a QR code on their smart phones and instantly start racing with custom made vertical slot car including Fiat Panda and Fiat 500&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">Fiat Smart Race is an interactive slot car racing game presented at İstanbul Autoshow 2012.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Opet ⇾ Infographic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opet-infographic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Opet ⇾ Infographic" /><published>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opet-infographic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opet-infographic/">&lt;p&gt;We created this infographic piece for Opet, a Turkish petroleum company founded in 1992.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We created this infographic piece for Opet, a Turkish petroleum company founded in 1992.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Akfel ⇾ WGC Paris Multitouch Application</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Akfel ⇾ WGC Paris Multitouch Application" /><published>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/akfel-wgc-paris-multitouch-application/">&lt;p&gt;We have developed and produced interactive multi touch tables for Akfel, an energy company based in Istanbul, Turkey. For the 2015 Paris World Gas Conference, they were looking for a way to showcase their portfolio, products, investments and subsidiaries within a manageable, interactive package. We have designed user interfaces, 3d graphics and illustrations for a massive content. Visualized many parts both in 3d and 2d graphics while sketching physical table designs proposals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have installed an alternative physical interface, a knob to control the flow of the information on the screen. While users were able to control everything through multi touch screen, the alternative knob made it more convenient  to scroll through in-depth information with a circular finger movement. Custom made knob cnc-machined from 7xxx series aluminum and fed the OpenFrameworks application which the whole application developed in through a micro controller.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We have developed and produced interactive multi touch tables for Akfel, an energy company based in Istanbul, Turkey. For the 2015 Paris World Gas Conference, they were looking for a way to showcase their portfolio, products, investments and subsidiaries within a manageable, interactive package. We have designed user interfaces, 3d graphics and illustrations for a massive content. Visualized many parts both in 3d and 2d graphics while sketching physical table designs proposals.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nice to Have ⇾ Product Design, Branding, Photography</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/nicetohave-product-design-branding-photography/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nice to Have ⇾ Product Design, Branding, Photography" /><published>2015-06-08T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-06-08T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nice-to-have-product-design-branding-photography</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/nicetohave-product-design-branding-photography/">&lt;p&gt;In 2012 we co-founded the brand called “Nice to Have”, “producing delicately created objects for fine living”. First collection and online shop was launched in 2015, after a short period of time opened a retail store in İstanbul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you feel about an object is important, sometimes we encounter a few that we have to use even we don’t like. We believe that the objects people own in their lives, are small reflections of how they choose to live it or had to..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We appreciate conscious consumption, investing in quality and the idea of owning things for life. Our goal is to create objects that are pleasing to the eye for years to come and durable enough for frequent uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the aspects of good design and aesthetics, user friendly experience is one of our priority. We produce our products using the best possible material and processing methods with local artisans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe in heritage of knowledge and experiences shape our lives. Learning is the key to keep our imagination alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may take a look at what we have been up to in our retail and online store.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">In 2012 we co-founded the brand called “Nice to Have”, “producing delicately created objects for fine living”. First collection and online shop was launched in 2015, after a short period of time opened a retail store in İstanbul.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Tilt Machine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Tilt Machine" /><published>2015-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-tilt-machine/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve created a motion tracking enabled, physical tilt game for Türkiye İş Bankası. Idea was to let people experience how easy it is to use bank’s mobile application for online banking just with a simple gesture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coin based game starts with a 1 Turkish Lira, after a coin inserted, one has to stand in the marked place and raise hand. When Kinect sensor acknowledges the person, a countdown begins and new “game coin” gets released from the slot to top left path. Goal is to get the coin through all the banking operations which are Money Transfer, Investment and Saving. We named these three as gates and each gate had its own attitude. If a coin slides into money transfer, another coin releases from opposite side or if it slides into investment gate, it spits out two coins to go on with. In the end users win the game when both coins slides into savings gate. Eventually the coin acceptor releases the initial real coin user inserted to start the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall it was another challenging project. As we needed to control single axis motion of a structure in realtime, we installed a 12 Nm industrial stepper motor coupled with 1:100 reduction gear right in the centre of structure origin. Rotating part was about 2 meters high, 1 meter wide and weigh around 180 kilograms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 10 Hitec servos running together to control all 6 flags, 3 coin release slots and the coin acceptor’s real coin slide out channel. Two units of 25 rpm dc motors used for the propellers and 1500 neopixel led’s running on four led micro controllers. In total there were three Arduino Uno and one Arduino Mega used to control the whole electro mechanical system. Microsoft Kinect was used for the real time motion tracking technology as physical controlling interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had 10 Hitec servos running together to control all 6 flags, 3 coin release slots and the coin acceptor’s real coin slide out channel. Two units of 25 rpm dc motors used for the propellers and 1500 neopixel led’s running on four led micro controllers. In total there were three Arduino Uno and one Arduino Mega used to control the whole electro mechanical system. Microsoft Kinect was used for the real time motion tracking technology as physical controlling interface.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve created a motion tracking enabled, physical tilt game for Türkiye İş Bankası. Idea was to let people experience how easy it is to use bank’s mobile application for online banking just with a simple gesture.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Valentine’s Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-valentines-day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ Valentine’s Day" /><published>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-walentines-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-valentines-day/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation based on real-time heartbeat detection on 14th of February for Valentine’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to promote bank’s touch-id integration for it’s iOS mobile applications. Users were drawn by a space with led illuminated tubes and an iPad screen asking ‘Who your heart beats for?’. When users fill in their and lover’s name, they were asked to place their finger on a heartbeat sensor as an input to refer touch-id action and data transaction through finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An animation with full of hearts gets triggered and projected on a huge wall and as they watch the animation, his/her excitement of love calculated with heartbeats in real-time. In the end of the animation their names were on the wall with the calculated heartbeats and cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side, we’ve used several addressable led’s, few led controllers, a pulse sensor, an Arduino and wireless communication to the computer on the projector side (which was hidden in an apartment flat) with an OpenFrameworks application.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation based on real-time heartbeat detection on 14th of February for Valentine’s Day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ İşBox Kinect</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Türkiye İş Bankası ⇾ İşBox Kinect" /><published>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-02-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/turkiye-is-bankasi-isbox-kinect/">&lt;p&gt;We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation featuring real-time and pre-defined skeleton tracking and matching based on human recognition using Xbox Kinect in February 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our goal was to create an interactive game to promote bank’s Kinect controlled, console based banking application for Xbox One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a shooting in studio with a choreographer and two performers, creating six different clips featuring various banking figures for three music genres. While doing this we also recorded performers skeleton data in order to match the real-time input generated by a participant in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20 or more banking and dancing figures were targeted for each song and if participant’s were good enough to act exactly or nearly the same, they were motivated with supers associated with banking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When playing, we took their photos and printed out like a transaction receipt when they are finished.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We’ve created an interactive pop-up installation featuring real-time and pre-defined skeleton tracking and matching based on human recognition using Xbox Kinect in February 2015.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aygaz ⇾ Step Into The Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/aygaz-step-into-the-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aygaz ⇾ Step Into The Future" /><published>2014-07-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-07-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/aygaz-step-into-the-future.md</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/aygaz-step-into-the-future/">&lt;p&gt;Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach was capturing audience attention on the field with an unexpected object, a space capsule coming from the future with a message in it. The message was composed of three key future projections; Climate Change, Health and Economics in the future. Story focus and our goal were to raise awareness and target emotional, perceptual experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 21st of May, we had the approval of capsule designs, materials, construction plans, key visuals and concept overall. Except we had no storyboard and two months to deliver the thing on the field. To cover up roughly we built a 4 meters long, 2.3 meters wide and 2.2 meters high made of aluminium space capsule looking experience area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We planted five LCD TV’s inside, three of them were the main screens which was feed by a multitouch application streaming 3240 x 1920 pixels of data and two of them were on the sides acting as a control panel, status updates and fictional settings. Again on both sides, we had 8 highlighted subjects in seven segment displays. Displaying real-time numbers of deaths today, births today, deaths caused by cancer and deaths caused by the hunger for instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each topic had 35 to 45 seconds of animation content to narrate the story, at the end of each scene, users faced with an interactive 3d world geometry to go through the details of just explained. For example after the Climate Change scene an interactive scenario opens up to let user browse the drastic escalation of carbon dioxide and nitrogen emission between 1956 to 2056. Throughout the story every crucial detailed data was mined from various articles, reports, future projections and documentaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall journey actually starts with a push of a button on the back side of the space capsule. When button kicks in an automatic door opens up while sending a signal to an Arduino board which triggers another Arduino board with two real time clocks to light up seven segments. Another signal goes to main PC which runs the multitouch application and video feed to initialize the welcome screen. Third signal going from the main Arduino board to the second PC which runs the side screens. Fourth signal goes to led control panel for lighting the ceiling which is responsive to the current content playing on main screens which makes led control panel synced in realtime to the main pc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes it was a complicated setup and in the end we found our self controlling every bit with a network of Arduino’s talking each other even when logging out from the capsule. There is a button inside which is yellow by the way, when you press that button, automatic doors opens up, system shuts down and CCTV stops operating until the next push from outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 52 days of sleepless nights, lots of calories and chain of events ruled by Murphy we delivered the space capsule on time for the roadshow. It was a huge experience for all of us and full of education on every step of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">Around April 2014, we started sketching out various space capsule designs based on the brief coming from the agency. It was for a roadshow that an automotive LPG company called Aygaz Otogaz going for.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ajans Press ⇾ Courier Ad</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ajans-press-courier-ad/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ajans Press ⇾ Courier Ad" /><published>2014-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-04-10T23:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ajans-press-courier-ad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ajans-press-courier-ad/">&lt;p&gt;Ajans Press, the pioneer and leader of media monitoring business in Turkey, has been providing service since the day it was founded in 1953. In addition to press, television, radio and internet monitoring and media analysis service, Ajans Press also provides news agency monitoring, sectoral agenda, tape-scripting and translation services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We designed and directed a TV Ad for their new courier service “Ajans Press Kurye”, the new company focuses on cooperative distribution of promotional materials etc.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">Ajans Press, the pioneer and leader of media monitoring business in Turkey, has been providing service since the day it was founded in 1953. In addition to press, television, radio and internet monitoring and media analysis service, Ajans Press also provides news agency monitoring, sectoral agenda, tape-scripting and translation services.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Avon ⇾ Fighting Breast Cancer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/avon-fighting-breast-cancer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Avon ⇾ Fighting Breast Cancer" /><published>2014-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-03-10T22:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/avon-fighting-breast-cancer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/avon-fighting-breast-cancer/">&lt;p&gt;We made this infographic animation with Avon Turkey for national cancer week. Explaning current aspects of breast cancer in the world and in Turkey while highlighting what has been done in the manner of fighting with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Avon, it is the longest running social responsibility project in Turkey as it’s been 18 years. Donations, fundraising, walks for awareness, seminars, free mammography scans, breast cancer research and education for self-diagnosis are just some of these actions to name.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Özgür Atmaca</name></author><summary type="html">We made this infographic animation with Avon Turkey for national cancer week. Explaning current aspects of breast cancer in the world and in Turkey while highlighting what has been done in the manner of fighting with it.</summary></entry></feed>